CV of Artur Teixeira August 2021



# **Artur Teixeira**

+351 911 076 566 https://artur-teixeira.tech/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/arturjnt/ https://twitter.com/arturjnt Rua Central de Salgueirinhos 530 4620-285 Lustosa Lousada Portugal

### **Summary**

Working since 2014 on Software, I've been through every job on the field, from a ticket-grabbing developer, through full-stack, infrastructure, database management, continuous delivery, frontend and backend engineering, and even information security.

I've managed teams of 1 to 15 people of various fields of expertise such as Design, Data Science, Quality Assurance and Engineering and I was quite lucky to work with some of the best in the business.

Working directly with business owners and clients is something I have years of experience in, therefore I understand the value of translating a vision into an actionable roadmap and its features.

Bringing you value is my passion, that's why I build stuff.

#### **Experience**

<u>Self-Employed</u> | Freelance Software Engineer (July 2021 - Now)

I will discuss, organize and develop apps and websites for anyone that needs to bootstrap a business or kickstart an idea.

For more information please check my website: <a href="https://artur-teixeira.tech/">https://artur-teixeira.tech/</a>

skeeled | Head of R&D (March 2017 - June 2021)

Software Engineering, Quality Assurance, UI/UX Design and Data Science team management, for the development of the best online recruitment platform.

- Lead technology teams in day-to-day operations, provide key expertise, supervise the heads of departments, and set performance goals.
- Conduct technical reviews of products or solutions to compare and evaluate their applicability.
- Contribute to the senior management team, guiding strategic decisions and resource allocation.
- Monitor management of all hardware, software, databases and licenses, maintenance, and projections of future needs.
- Integrate and communicate with third-parties to ensure processes and expectations are met.
- People Management.
- Architecture of code using engineering patterns.
- Scrum and Kanban methodologies.

CV of Artur Teixeira August 2021

skeeled | Lead Software Engineer (November 2015 - February 2017)

Working in the architecture, development and deployment of the skeeled web recruitment platform.

- Frontend developed in the following languages: AngularJS (JavaScript), HTML5 & Sass (CSS3). Assisted by the following tools: Grunt, NPM, Bower, Bootstrap & others.
- Backend using NodeJS & Express (previously developed in Java, assisted by Maven & Dropwizard)
- NoSQL MongoDB database mLab online MongoDB host (MongoDB-as-a-Service)

## DevOps:

- Amazon Web Services (AWS) S3, EC2 & Code Deploy
- CodeShip CI (Continuous Integration)
- Rollbar error logging on various environments
- PM2 Keymetrics real time machine overview

## Other technologies include:

- git source control
- JIRA (previously Pivotal Tracker) project management

TOP Docs | Full Stack Dev (April 2015 - October 2015)

Working in the (Full Stack) development of TopDocs platform for iOS & Web.

#### Languages:

- Java (Android)
- JavaScript (NodeJS, AngularJS & ExpressJS)
- SASS (Bootstrap)
- PHP & ShellScript;

#### DevOps:

- Working in Azure Web Apps & Virtual Machines (Linux);
- Data modeling in SQL (MySQL) and NoSQL (MongoDB);
- Use of Instruments Automation tool for iOS "black box" tests;
- Extensive use of GIT version control tool;

Presence in UlKonf 2015 and Microsoft Azure Camp for BizSpark Startups about infrastructure.

<u>Jumia Porto Tech Center (Rocket Internet)</u> | PHP Dev (September 2014 - April 2015)

Supporting the development of an e-commerce application.

Working with technologies such as PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL and Solr.

Also with Yii and Zend frameworks backed by git version control.

CV of Artur Teixeira August 2021

## Languages

- Native Portuguese
- Fluent English
- Limited proficiency in Spanish

#### **Skills**

Web Node.js | Vue.js | HTML | CSS | SASS
DBs MongoDB (NoSQL) | SQL | Firebase

Mobile Flutter | Dart

• Infrastructure AWS (S3, EC2, etc) | OVH (VPS)

CI/CD Jenkins

Management Tools Git | JIRA | Trello | Miro | ProductBoard | Draw.io

IT Security
GDPR(DPIAs) | ISO Certifications | Pen-Tests | Cookie Law

#### **Education**

Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto (ISEP) BSc Informatics Engineering (2011-2014)

Introduction to several languages such as Assembly, C, C++, Shell Script, Flex, Bison, Java, C#, Prolog, PHP, XML, XHTML, XSLT, HTML and Oracle SQL.

Also developed notions in OpenGL, .NET, MVC, MVVM and Scrum.

In terms of Software Engineering achieved knowledge in GoF and GRASP patterns, having know-how in Architecture Diagrams such as User Stories, Class, Sequence, Domain Model, Deployment View and more.